Bong Chong Hiang

Summary

11 years in the IT industry:

During this period, I have excelled in various supporting roles, developing a keen ability to **troubleshoot** issues **systematically** and **efficiently**. My accumulated work-experiences has enabled me to learn and adapt quickly to new technologies and processes, ensuring **minimal downtime** and **optimal performance** at the workplace.

3 years in the Engineering industry:

Here, I have diversified my expertise by taking on both developing and supporting roles. This experience has broadened my skillsets, allowing me to understand in terms of engineering projects and contribute to their successful completion.

In addition to my professional experience, I am proactively enhancing my skills and competencies through online learning. Most recently I acquired the skills and knowledge in full stack development conducted by Generation Singapore. Having undergone rigorous training and contributing extensively to the development of a capstone project in JavaScript, Java and Spring Boot. I am enthusiastic and better-prepared to embark on a career in web and internet application development.

Mobile : 90074733

Email : chbong33@ymail.com

Citizenship. : Singaporean

linkedin.com/in/chong-hiang-bong

github.com/bong033

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Cobol, Pascal, Basic, Node Red, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS,

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Diagnostic Tools: CLI

RECENT ACCOMPLISHMENT

Power Monitoring Solutions — Node Red, MySQL

Dashboard to: -

- Display real time data for current, voltage, power etc.
- Display historical data for current,
- voltage, power etc.
- Calculate total cost for selected duration period.

LANGUAGES

SPEAKS: English | Mandarin

WRITES: English

EXPERIENCE

Precision Motion Control Pte Ltd — Assistant Application Engineer

Aug 2021 - Feb 2024

- **Guide** customers in troubleshooting Schneider product issues, such as connectivity and configuration via Modbus TCP/RTU, OPC UA.
- Develop and debug demo/Schneider software testing on IEC 61131/61499 (Schneider PLC/HMI programming).
- Proactively participate in evaluating new products and emerging technologies.
- Developed training documentation on PLC programming for external customers.
- **Spearheaded** the development of a software solution for Power Monitoring Devices using Java, Node-Red, MySQL and Schneider Application Software.

Anglo-Sima Janitorial Supplies Pte Ltd — Robotics Engineer

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

- Demonstrate new deployment and troubleshooting for Autonomous Cleaning Robot.
- Develop and refine mapping solutions .
- Execute path planning using Teach & Follow/Auto Cover.
- Analyze and interpret data from 2D/3D lidar and ultrasonic sensors.

Robotics Automation Centre in Excellence — *Trainee*

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021

- Design basic part models and assemblies using Solidworks.
- Implement and optimize rotary motor and direct drive linear motor.
- Apply motor sizing principles and integrate basic PID concepts.
- Evaluate a wide range of bearings, including deep groove, air and angular contact bearings.
- Employ Strategic Thinking, Design Thinking and SCRUM methodologies.
- Simulate basic factory operations using Visual Component 4.2.
- Utilize XYZ slicer for Additive Manufacturing applications.
- Program and configure PLCs with Universal Robot/Hanwha via Raspberry Pi.

Talariax Pte Ltd - Singapore — Technical Support Executive

Jul 2019 - Apr 2020

- Configure and deploy SMS Gateway systems.
- Install and integrate POC/Rail mounting using SMTP, SNMP Trap, Syslog, ICMP protocol.
- Conduct hardware refreshes and migrate data from EOL appliances.
- Maintain systems through patching and updates..
- Diagnose and resolve network connectivity issues using advanced diagnostic tools.
- **Document** processes and **report** findings comprehensively.

PROFESSIONAL / INDUSTRY CERTIFICATE

NTUC LEARNINGHUB PTE LTD

NICF – MTA Windows Server Administration Fundamentals (PCP) (SF)

NICF - MTA Security Fundamentals (PCP) (SF)

NICF - MTA Networking Fundamentals (PCP) (SF)

NICF - Linux Command Line and Shell Scripting (PCP) (SF)

NICF - Cisco CCNA Routing & Switching Part 1 (CCENT, ICND1) (PCP) (SF)

NICF - Cisco CCNA Routing & Switching Part 2 (CCENT, ICND2) (PCP) (SF)

Dec 2019

EDUCATION

Central Queensland University — *Degree of Bachelor in Computing*Mar 1998

Informatics Computer School — *NCC Diploma in Computer Studies*Dec 1993

Singapore Technical Institute — *ITC Electronic Engineering*